

Strengths

Leadership – Demonstrated this at Salute iWorld. I was the store manager and led my team to become the best-improved and best-selling store. I also always take the initiative to be the team leader in hackathons.

Quick Learner – Demonstrated this in my role as a Graphics designer. I was required to learn graphics design so as to be fully absorbed into the company as an intern. In less than 2 months, I was designing different things for the company e.g., Billboards, banners, the company website etc.

Problem solver and decisive with Limited information – I have demonstrated this in 3 major hackathons that I have attended. Having to develop an idea quickly, build it and win tests someone's problem-solving and decision-making skills.

Communication – As an Apple consultant, with 2yrs experience, I have developed exceptional communication skills. I engaged customers, understood their needs, and provided tailored solutions to them. With a proven track record of winning the Best Employee award a couple of times.

Positive attitude - Proven ability to maintain a positive attitude and mindset, even under challenging circumstances

I have a track record of working independently and collaboratively.

Employment History

Software developer at Selluh Tech Insurance, Nairobi

JANUARY 2022 — FEBRUARY 2023

Insurance-Tech early-stage Startup in Nairobi.

We are building an insurance underwriting system that underwrites individual business, corporate business, and Fund management.

- Build the mobile system using React Native (Android and IOS).
- I use Electron to build the Desktop version.
- Work on the front-end team using React.JS.
- Responsible for bug fixing and software analysis.
- Contribute to design changes and adding features.

Apple Solutions Consultant-Store Manager, Salute iWorld, Nairobi

OCTOBER 2020 — OCTOBER 2022

IT Specialist and Graphics Designer, Salute Holdings LTD, Nairobi

AUGUST 2019 — SEPTEMBER 2020

Details

WEBSITE:
davidmbugua.netlify.app
Nairobi, Kenya
+254 790 362962
davidnginyo11@gmail.com

LinkedIn_(click these)
GitHub
Medium

SKILLS

LANGUAGES

JavaScript| TypeScript|
Python| Dart| HTML5| CSS|
SQL| MongoDB

TECHNOLOGIES

React JS | Vue.JS | Angular Node JS | Flutter | React Native Firebase | Bootstrap | Git | Rest APIs | Figma | Jest | Pixi JS Application & Web Servers

OTHERS

Design Thinking | Agile Software development | CRUD | Adobe illustrator & XD | MVC architecture | Functional Programming | Object Oriented Programming

TOOLS

VS Code | Android Studio | XCode IntelliJ | PyCharm | GitHub | Netlify & Vercel | Stack Overflow | Markdown

Hobbies

Travelling, Hiking, driving, Listening to and discovering new Music.

Languages

English

Swahili

Education

Full Stack Software Development, Ubunifu College, Nairobi

AUG 2021 — MAY 2022

Ubunifu College of AI (Full Stack Software Development)

- Developed skills in front-end development using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Figma, and React JS.
- Developed skills in back-end development using Firebase, Node JS, Express, MongoDB, SQL and Python.

Information Technology, Zetech University, Nairobi

MAY 2018 — JUNE 2019

Joined Zetech to pursue a diploma in IT

KCSE, Highway Secondary, Nairobi

FEBRUARY 2014 — DECEMBER 2017

KCPE, The Nairobi Primary School, Nairobi

JANUARY 2005 — NOVEMBER 2013

Online Courses

MySQL, Self-taught
Dart-Flutter, Self-taught
Agile Methodology, IBM

Design thinking Practitioner, IBM

JANUARY 2022 — FEBRUARY 2022

Hackathons

PLP Africa Power Hacks - link

Participated and became 2nd Runners up at a hackathon by PLPAfrica.

The theme was #powerhacks where were supposed to think of an existing problem on the fly and build a solution using computing.

- Built a full mobile app using flutter for an agro-tech idea we named Shamba Fresh where we help farmers know the best crops to farm depending on their types of soil (using soil science) and the weather.
- Leveraged AI using a chatbot API that can give farmers real-time solutions to any problems they might have.
- became 2nd Runners up seniors against 19 other teams.

DECENTRALAND METAVERSE HACKATHON - click here

Participated in the Metaverse Hackathon by Decentraland, a 72-hour event where I led a team of five developers to design and build a multiplayer game in the metaverse.

- Developed games using TypeScript, and the Decentraland SDK
- Designed interactive wearables for users and created 3D models

- using Blender.
- Implemented a real-time communication system to enable multiplayer gameplay using WebSocket.
- Overcoming technical challenges to deliver a smooth and responsive experience.
- Our team's game won the award for Best Use of Decentraland's SDK and is being featured on Decentraland's official website.

PLP Africa Water Day hackathon

- Participated and won the water day hackathon which was a 5 day virtual hackathon across different participants in Africa.
 Built a mobile app using flutter for our project named WabaYetu(our water), where we help people identify safe water drinking areas and water treatment spots within a region.
- I built a website for the project with information about our work and a link to our app.
- My team won the best idea overall and the best mobile project in the hackathon.

Projects

Kindly visit my portfolio at https://davidmbugua.netlify.app/ to view my projects.

I am an active contributor to open-source projects, leveraging collaborative development to deliver innovative software solutions, demonstrate expertise in coding practices, and contribute to the open-source community.

Community

- ReactDevsKe
- Google Developers Group Nairobi
- NodeJS Nairobi
- Young founders' space

Volunteering

Divisional Superintended - St. John Ambulance.

I am a first Aid instructor and Drill trainer, training St. John Cadets in high school.

I have trained teams that managed to win the national first aid and drill competitions thrice since 2017.

Education Support Volunteer – Ubunifu College.

Taught HTML, CSS, Vanilla JavaScript and firebase to students at Ubunifu College in Nairobi.

Completed 80+ hours of teaching and enabled an increase in their academic score.